Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Communist and Socialist Serials TAM.747
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: International Publications, 1850-2013; cuid11440; 52.6 Linear Feet in 89 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 47 flat boxes
  - Subseries II.B: Other International Publications, 1850-2013; 52.6 Linear Feet in 89 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 47 flat boxes
    - Kommunistische Korrespondenz: Trotzkistischen Liga Deutschlands, Berlin, Germany, 1976; cuid13221 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Social Democrat: Twentieth Century Press, London, England, 1930 (Box 213, Folder 10)
    - Politiek en Cultuur: Uitgeverij Pegasus, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1988, 1990, 1991; cuid13222 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - De Meningsverschillen in De Communistische Wereldbeweging: Uitgeverij Pegasus Amsterdam, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1983; cuid13223 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ukranian Bureau Bulletin: Ukranian Bureau, London, England, 1931-1934; cuid13224 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Class Struggle = Lutte de Classe: Union Communiste/Lutte Ouvriere, Paris, France, 1973, 1975-1979; cuid13225 (Box 71, Folder 1-4)
    - Insiders: A Discussion Pamphlet on Social Ownership: Universities and Left Review/ R. Prince Magdalen College, London, England, circa 1950s; cuid13226 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Perspectives: University of Sussex Socialist Club, Sussex, England, 1966, 1968; cuid13227 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Vanguard: Vanguard, London, England, 1965; cuid13228 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Canada/US Relations: A Socialist Viewpoint: Vanguard Publications, Ontario, Canada, 1969; cuid13229 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Verhandlungen des Deutschen Reichstages: Verhandlungen des Deutschen Reichstages, Germany, 1888 (Box 253, Folder 3)
    - Bericht der Russischen Sozial-Revolutionaren Partei an den Internationalen Sozialistenkongress zu Stuttgart: Verlag der Russischen Sozial-Revolutionaren Partei, 1907 (Box 231, Folder 10)
    - Bericht uber die Verhandlungen des III. (8.) Parteitages der Kommunistischen Partei Deutschlands: Vereinigung Internationaler Verlags, Berlin, Germany, 1923 (Box 253, Folder 1)
    - Protokoll des 15. Parteitages der KPdSU: Verlag Carl Hoym Nachf, Hamburg, Germany, 1927 (Box 240, Folder 5)
    - Hauptwerke des Sozialismus und der Sozialpolitik: Verlag con C.L. Hirschfeld, Leipzig, Germany, 1904, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1911; cuid13230 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Der zweite Kongren der Kommunistischen Internationale: Verlag der Arbeiter-Buchhandlung, Vienna, Austria, 1920; cuid13231 (Box 73, Folder 13, Box 225, Folder 6-7)
    - Protokoll des 4. Parteitages der Kommunistischen Partei Oesterreichs (Sektion der Kommunistischen Internationale): Verlag der Arbeiterbuchhandlung, Vienna, Austria, 1921-1922 (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - Der Kampf un die Massen: Verlag der Jugendinternationale, Berlin, Germany, 1930; cuid13232 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Geschichte der Kommunistischen Jugendinternationale: Verlag der Jugendinternationale, Berlin, Germany, 1931; cuid13233 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Almanach: Verlag der Kommunistischen Internationale, Hamburg, Germany, undated (Box 204, Folder 2)
    - Leitsatze und Statuten der Kommunistischen Internationale: Verlag der Kommunistischen Internationale, Hamburg, Germany, 1920 (Box 228, Folder 14)
    - Protokoll des II. Welfkongresses der Kommunistischen Internationale: Verlag der Kommunistischen Internationale, Hamburg, Germany, 1921 (Box 241, Folder 1)
    - Dokumente des socialismus: Verlag der Sozialistischen Monatshefte, Berlin, Germany, 1905; cuid13234 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Soczialistischen Bucherei: Verlag der Wiener Volksbuchhandlung Ignaz Brand & Co., Vienna, Austria, 1919; cuid13235 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Die Entwicklung des Sozialismus von der Utopie zur Wissenschaft: Verlag JHW Dietz Nachfolger Berlin, Berlin, Germany, 1931; cuid13236 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Handbuch Sozialdemokratischer Landes-Parteitage in Sachsen: Verlag Landesvorsland der Sozialdemokratischen Partei, Leipzig, Germany, 1914 (Box 253, Folder 4)
    - Kritik des Gothaer Programms: Verlag Neuer Weg G.m.b.H., Berlin, Germany, 1946; cuid13237 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Der Sozialist: Verlag Tony Breitscheid, Berlin, Germany, 1922; cuid13238 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Klassenkampf und Nation: Verlag von Runge & Co., Reichenberg, Czech Republic, 1912; cuid13239 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Die Sozialistische Arbeiter-Internationale: Verlag: Buchhandlung Vorwarts, Berlin, Germany, 1907; cuid13240 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Die Sozialdemokratie im Deutschen Reichstag: Verlag: Buchhandlung Vorwarts, Berlin, Germany, 1909 (Box 225, Folder 5)
    - Sozialdemokratische Flugschriften: Verlag: Buchhandlung Vorwarts Paul Singer, Berlin, Germany, 1911-1913; cuid13241 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Gegen Den sztrom: Verlag: Junius-Verlag, Berlin, Germany, 1930; cuid13242 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Internationaler Sozialisten Kongreb: Verlag: Vuchhandlung Vorwarts, Berlin, Germany, 1907 (Box 231, Folder 9)
    - Ergänzungshefte zur Neuen Zeit: Verlag und Druck von Paul Singer, Stuttgart, Germany, 1914; cuid13369 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Die russische Revolution und die sozialistische Internationale: Verlagsbuchhandlung Karl Zwing, Jena, Germany, 1932; cuid13243 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Die Kommunistische Internationale vor Dem VII. Weltkongress: Verlagsgenossenschaft Auslandischer Arbeiter in der UdSSR, Moscow, USSR, 1935 (Box 226, Folder 3)
    - Small Man, Big World: A Discussion of Socialist Democracy: Victoria House Printing Co. Ltd. / Labour Publications Department, London, England, 1949; cuid13244 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Bloc: Voice of Central and Eastern Europe: Voice of Solidarity, London, England, 1989; cuid13245 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Class Struggle: Voix Ouvriere, Paris, France, 1967; cuid13246 (Box 72, Folder 1-2, Box 103, Folder 24, Box 248, Folder 1)
    - Ideologica: Voz Proletaria, Bogota, Colombia, 1972; cuid13247 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Juventud: Voz Proletaria, Bogota, Colombia, 1972; cuid13248 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Buiten de Orde: Vrijie Bond, Holland, 1990; cuid13249 (Box 11, Folder 1, Box 232, Folder 8)
    - Campus Bolshevik: VUW Bolshevik Club, Wellington, New Zealand, 1991-1992, 1996, 2000; cuid13250 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Workers' Weekly: W. Tait, Edinburgh, Scotland, 1944-1945 (Box 248, Folder 3)
    - Protokoll des Parteitages 1922: Wiener Boltsbuchhandlung, Vienna, Austria (Box 244, Folder 1)
    - Protokoll des Parteitages 1923: Wiener Boltsbuchhandlung, Vienna, Austria (Box 244, Folder 3)
    - Spark: WIR Publications/ The University of Sussex Socialist Club, London, England, 1967-1968; cuid13251 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Geschicte der Volkswirtschaftslehre II: Der Sozialismus und die Sozialisierung: Wirtschaftswissenschaft, 1949; cuid13252 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Review: Wm. S. Ainsworth, Birmingham, England, circa 1940s; cuid13253 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Worker Today: Worker Today, Stockholm, Sweden, 1991; cuid13254 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - International: Worker-communist Party of Iran, London, England, 1992; cuid13255 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Forge: Workers Communist Party (Marxist-Leninist), Montreal, Canada, 1980; cuid13256 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Workers Fight: Workers Fight, England, 1972; cuid13257 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Permanent Revolution: Workers' Fight, London, England, 1973; cuid13258 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Revolutionary Communist: Workers International League, Johannesburg, South Africa, 1945; cuid13259 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Does Russia's Entry Alter Britain's War?: Workers' International League Fourth International, London, England, circa 1960s; cuid13260 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Trade Union in the Epoch of Imperialist Decay: Workers' International League Fourth International, London, England, circa 1950s; cuid13261 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Trade Unions in the Epoch of Imperialist Decay: Workers' International Press, London, England, 1941; cuid13262 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Soviet Russia Pictorial: Workers' International Relief/Centropress Ltd. and British Joint Labour Aid Committee of the Workers' International Relief, London, England, 1924; cuid13263 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Class, The Party and The Leadership: Workers' International Review, London, England, circa 1960s; cuid13264 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Workers International Review: Workers' International Review, London, England, 1957; cuid13265 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Experiences of the left - Marxism & the labour movement: Workers' Liberty Education Department - Socialist Organiser, London, England, 1999; cuid13266 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Workers News: Workers News, London, England, 1992; cuid13267 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Constituency News: Workers Party of Jamaica South St. Andrew Constituency Executive, Kingston, Jamaica, 1984; cuid13268 (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - Spanish Revolution: Workers' Party of Marxist Unification, Barcelona, Spain, 1937; cuid13269 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Spark: Workers' Party of South Africa, Cape Town, South Africa, 1935-1939 (Box 242, Folder 11-15)
    - Umlilo Mollo: Workers Party of South Africa/ Lee, R., Johannesburg, South Africa, 1936; cuid13270 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Workers Power: Workers Power Group, London, England, 1979; cuid13271 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Workers Power: Workers Power Group, London, England, 1982; cuid13272 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Workers' Research Unit Bulletin: Workers' Research Unit, Belfast, Ireland, circa 1970s; cuid13273 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Workers Socialist Review: Workers' Socialist League, London, England, 1981-1982; cuid13274 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Workers Socialist Review: Workers' Socialist Review, London, England, circa 1970s; cuid13275 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Dynamics of world Revolution Today: Workers Vanguard Publishing Association, Ontario, Canada, 1964; cuid13276 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Workers Vanguard: Workers' Vanguard Publishing Association/ League for Socialist Action, Toronto, Canada, 1962, 1965, 1969; cuid13277 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Information Bulletin: World Marxist Review Publishers, Canada, 1968; cuid13325 (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - Internationale: Workers of All Lands Unite: Young Communist League of Great Britain, Northolt, England, circa 1960s; cuid13278 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Plebs: Young Fabian Group, London, England, 1973; cuid13279 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Anticipations: Young Fabians Magazine, London, England, 2013; cuid13280 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Middle East Coexistence: Young MAPAM/The Narod Press, London, England, 1970; cuid13281 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Young Socialist Forum: Young Socialist Forum Publishing Association, Toronto, Canada, circa 1950s; cuid13282 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Young Socialist Forum: Young Socialist Forum Publishing Association, Toronto, Canada, 1967; cuid13283 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Position of the Republic and the Tasks of Young Workers: Young Socialists, London, England, 1972; cuid13284 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - Young Socialist: Young Socialists, Toronto, Ontario, 1971 (Box 218, Folder 8)
    - News Line: Young Socialists/ News Line, London, England, 1976-1978, 1980; cuid13285 (Box 76, Folder 1-4)
    - REBEL: YS/ Rebel Publications Association, London, England, circa 1960s; cuid13286 (Box 2, Folder 18, Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Der Kapitalismus und das informationszeitalter: Zeitschrift Sozialismus, Hamburg, Germany, 1996; cuid13287 (Box 72, Folder 24)
    - [Greek-language newspaper], 1976; cuid13288 (Box 2, Folder 22-25)
    - 10월의교훈및이행기강령 / 10-wŏl ŭi kyohun mit ihaenggi kangnyŏng: Seoul, South Korea, 1996; cuid13289 (Box 72, Folder 25)
    - Akademie Revue Socialisticka, 1924; cuid13290 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Bresche: Das Sozialistische Magazin: Zurich, Germany, 1991-1992; cuid13291 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin du Secretariat Europeen de la IV Internationale, 1945; cuid13292 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Das Banner: Germany, Undated (Box 226, Folder 4)
    - Das Neue Russland, 1927; cuid13293 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - De Nieuwe Weg, 1934-1935; cuid13294 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Der Dritte Weg: Germany, 1963; cuid13295 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Der Sozialdemokratische: Berlin, Germany, 1893 (Box 226, Folder 1)
    - Deutschland-Information des Zentralkomitees der K.P.D., 1937-1938; cuid13296 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - El Diario, 1994; cuid13297 (Box 122, Folder 25)
    - Espana Obrera: Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1937; cuid13298 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Freie Sozialistische Blatter: Paris, France, 1949; cuid13299 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Front Ouvrier: Imprimerie Speciale de Front Ouvrier La Gerante, Paris, France, 1945; cuid13317 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Inhaltsverzeichnis, 1930; cuid13300 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Kirche im Sozialismus: Berlin, Germany, 1981; cuid13301 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - La Verite - Revue Trotskyste: Paris, France, 1961; cuid13302 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Labour Review, 1952-1954; cuid13303 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Le Peuple: Confederation Generale du Travail, Paris, France, circa 1940s; cuid13304 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - L'Ère nouvelle: Paris, France, 1934; cuid13305 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - L'Etincelle: Hebdomadaire Communiste Revolutionnaire, 1978; cuid13306 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - L'Exploite: Brusells, Belgium, 1911; cuid13307 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Noticiero Bolchevique: La Habana, Cuba, 1937; cuid13308 (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Pacific Tribune: Vancouver, Canada, 1983; cuid13309 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Prometeo: Brussels, Belgium, 1929-1930; cuid13310 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Red Republican: London, England, 1850; cuid13311 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Risorgimento Socialista: Rome, Italy, 1955-1956; cuid13312 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Service l'Information et de Presse pour la Quatrieme Internationale: Paris, France, 1936-1937; cuid13313 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Socialist Action: Wellington, New Zealand, 1970-1971; cuid13314 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Sozialistische Zeitung Magazin: Koln, Germany, 1998-2001; cuid13315 (Box 74, Folder 22, Box 151, Folder 4-5)
    - Urbeiter! Lies und dente!, circa 1940s; cuid13316 (Box 74, Folder 23)